麦琪:杰森,我要告诉你件事,你能答应我不许笑吗?
Maggie: Jason, if I tell you something, will you promise not to laugh?
杰森:当然可以.
Jason: Sure.
麦琪:我已经开始想迈克了.
Maggie: I miss Mike already.
杰森:对不起.啊,啊,鸡蛋还是饼?
Jason: Excuse me. Ah ha ha ha. Eggs or pancakes.
麦琪:你知道我想什么?我要告诉你我的想法,
Maggie: You know what I think? Well I'll tell you what I think.
我认为你也和我一样想迈克.
I think you miss Mike as much as I do.
杰森:亲爱的,他才搬出去七个小时,
Jason: Honey, he just moved out seven hours ago for crying out aloud.
你就开始大声抱怨了.他不过是在车库顶上.
And it's just over the garage.
麦琪:我觉得这是所有父母必须面对的,
Maggie: I guess this is something that all parents have to go through.
面对着这一天,他们的孩子离开了温暖的小窝,
Facing the day when their baby leaves the nest and doesn't need anything
然后不再需要他们的帮助.
from them anymore.
迈克:爸爸,我需要你的工具箱.
Mike: Dad I need your tool box.
杰森:在地下室,烘干机的后面.
Jason: Basement, behind the dryer.
迈克:好的,谢谢.
Mike: Alright thanks.
麦琪:迈克,吃饭了.
Maggie: Mike, have a meal.
迈克:对不起,妈妈,我没时间.
Mike: Sorry mum, no time. I have tons of work to do on my place.
我屋里这有一堆的事要做呢.相信我,
Believe me, you guys will not be disappointed.
你们不会失望的,我要像开萝尔一样独立,自己挣钱吃饭.
I am taking to independence like Carol takes to food.
杰森:还想他吗?
Jason: Still miss him?
开萝尔:大家早上好.这可是迈克第一个自由的早上,我喜欢.
Carol: Good morning all. The first Mike free morning. I love it.
迈克:在洗衣机还是烘干机后面?
Mike: Behind the washer or dryer?
杰森:烘干机.
Jason: Dryer.
开萝尔:我以为你走了.
Carol: I thought you moved?
迈克:我以为你洗过澡了呢.
Mike: I thought you showered.
麦琪:我要去给孩子穿衣服,开萝尔,你可以收拾一下桌子吧?
Maggie: Well I have to change the baby. Carol, will you set the table please?
开萝尔:昨天就是我做的,今天该轮到迈克了.
Carol: Well it was my day yesterday. Today is Mike's day.
杰森:迈克现在在他自己的屋里有些事,
Jason: Well Mike has chores at his own place now.
这些家务必须得调换一下.
Some of the load will have to shift.
开萝尔:什么每次需要调换的时候,倒霉的都是我?
Carol: So how come every time a load gets shifted, it plops on me?
杰森:开萝尔,我正在这做饭.
Jason: Carol, I'm trying to cook food here.
开萝尔:好,好,我不抱怨了.
Carol: Ok, ok, its beneath me to complain.
本:什么事情惹你了……
Ben: Anything beneath you...
开萝尔:要是你的话,你是不是会希望你从来没有出生,
Carol: One word from you, and you will wish, as I do,
和我一样.
that you'd never been born.
本:什么?
Ben: What?
开萝尔:现在迈克走了,轮到你欺负我了?
Carol: So now that Mike's gone, it's your job to insult me?
本:你好大的脾气.
Ben: You got it jumbo.
杰森:本!
Jason: Ben!
迈克:好了.电子磁带呢?
Mike: Alright. Electrical tape?
杰森:卧室顶头桌子的抽屉里.
Jason: Living room end table drawer.
迈克:谢谢.
Mike: Thanks.
杰森:哦,迈克,我们在这谈一下租房合同的事,你知道租金得……
Jason: Oh Mike. Just so we get this rental agreement off on the right foot here, you know that rent is due in...
迈克:提前.
Mike: In advance.
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yeah.
迈克:好的,谢谢.
Mike: Right, thanks.
杰森:那好,嗯,就今天吧,迈克.
Jason: That would, uh, be today Mike.
迈克:你是说马上?
Mike: What you mean like right now?
开萝尔:对.
Carol: Hu!
杰森:租金50元,迈克,你还少30.
Jason: That, uh, rent is fifty Mike. You're thirty short.
迈克:怎么会这样?那好,我马上回来.
Mike: Well how the heck could that be? Alright, I will be back in less than a minute.
本:哈!
Ben: Ha!
开萝尔:他说他要回来,不过他并没有说他有这钱.
Carol: He said that he'd be back. He didn't say that he'd have the money.
迈克:妈妈.
Mike: Mum.
麦琪:在这,宝贝?
Maggie: Yeah honey?
迈克:你好,克莉丝.妈妈,我在整理我的新家,我缺一些钱,要买些吃的,还有……
Mike: Hi Chris. You know mum, what with me fixing up my new place and all, I've kinda run a little out of money for food and...
麦琪:当然可以,宝贝,你需要多少?
Maggie: Of course sweetheart. How much do you need?
迈克:哦,只要30……40就更好了.
Mike: Oh, just thirt...Forty would be terrific.
迈克:30,40,50.
Mike: Thirty, forty and fifty.
杰森:恭喜你,迈克.
Jason: Well congratulations Mike.
你公寓的第一个月的租金,已经及时付清了.
You're first months rent on your first apartment, paid in full and on time.
迈克:以后会有很多次的.爸爸.
Mike: The first of many dad.
杰森:开萝尔,我觉得你应该对你哥哥有一点信心,
Jason: Carol, I think you should consider having a little more faith in
现在他已经独立了.
your brother now that he's out on his own.
麦琪:杰森,你还有钱吗?
Maggie: Jason, do you have any cash?
我要去购物,我刚把所有的钱都借给了迈克.
I need to go shopping and I just lent all mine to Mike.
杰森:迈克!
Jason: Mike!
迈克:嘿,爸爸,怎么了?
Mike: Hey dad. What's up?
杰森:你真是诡计多端.
Jason: Your scam. Did you really think it was alright to borrow your rent
你真的觉得从你妈妈那借钱付租金合适吗?
money from mum?
迈克:咦,你是怎么知道的?
Mike: Yeah. Hey could you hold this?
杰森:迈克.现在我们已经签订了一份关于你租房的合同,是的,我们都同意.现在,这是你的第一天,并且……
Jason: Mike, come on. Now we had an agreement about you renting, that we, uh, agreed to. Now here is your first day and...
迈克:是的,但是你没有规定我应该从哪里得到租金.
Mike: Yeah, but you didn't say anything about where I got the rent money.
杰森:我是没有,但是……
Jason: No, but come on.
迈克:你能把他拉紧点吧?
Mike: Can you pull it a little tighter?
杰森:可以.
Jason: Sure.
迈克:谢谢.
Mike: Thanks.
杰森:迈克,
Jason: Come on Mike.
之所以定这份合同,
Now the spirit of our agreement is that there is a price that you pay
是因为想让你依靠自己支付这租金.现在你在这,
to be on your own.
正在接到我们的有线电视,
An here you are, and right away, you're splicing into our cable TV,
是吗?
aren't you?
迈克:是的,你在帮我.
Mike: Yeah, and you're helping me.
杰森:迈克,那是错误的.
Jason: Mike, this is wrong.
迈克:那好,我不做,我去找本.
Mike: Well then don't do it. I'll just get Ben.
杰森:我们要谈一下.
Jason: We've got to talk.
迈克:什么事?现在?
Mike: What? Now?
杰森:是的,我们得整理一下这份合同,
Jason: Yes. We've got to get this agreement of our cleared up if it's
如果还要继续的话,如果你想继续的话.
to have any future, If you're going to have any future.
迈克:爸爸,我们能以后再谈吗?我还有一小时要上课了.
Mike: Dad, can we just talk about this later? I've got class in an hour.
杰森:不行!我们不行,我们……你说什么?
Jason: No! We can't. We..you've got a what?
迈克:一小时以后有课.
Mike: Class in an hour.
杰森:课?
Jason: Class?
迈克:对.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:好,可以,很好,行,你走吧.
Jason: Uh hu. Sure, no, good. Ok.
迈克:好的,谢谢你,爸爸.
Mike: Ok. Thanks. Hey dad.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
迈克:我只是想说我并不想向我妈借钱,那只是因为我真的想遵守我们的合同.
Mike: I just wanted to say that I didn't like borrowing that rent money from mum. It's just that I really wanted to honor our agreement.
杰森:嗯,遵守很好.
Jason: Uh hu. Honor's good.
迈克:好的,谢谢,再见.
Mike: Yeah thanks. See you later.
杰森:好的,没想到,
Jason: Well what do you know.
没想到,真没想到.
What do you know what do you know, what do you know wo wo.
麦琪:杰森!
Maggie: Jason!
杰森:听我说,你知道迈克刚才说什么了吗?
Jason: Listen to this. Do you know what Mike just said?
麦琪:迈克不在这儿,杰森,就你一个人上蹿下跳的.
Maggie: Mike's not here Jason and you're hopping up and down all alone.
杰森:不,他刚才在这.
Jason: No but he was here. Listen to this.
听我说,他说他要去上课.
He just said he was going to class.
麦琪:迈克,他?
Maggie: Mike who?
杰森:我们的儿子.还有呢,
Jason: Our son. That's not all.
他还说他想遵守我们的合同,我可没有编造.
He also said that he wanted to honor our agreement. I'm not making this up.
麦琪:喔.
Maggie: Wow.
杰森:并且,
Jason: And, he also apologized for borrowing the rent money from you so
他还因为向你借钱付租金向我道歉.
he could pay the rent.
麦琪:那就是他要这钱的原因?
Maggie: That's why he wanted the money?
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yeah.
麦琪:但是他要买吃的,他对我撒了谎.
Maggie: But he said that was for food. He lied to me.
杰森:他意识到了.
Jason: He realizes that.
麦琪:当然他意识到了,那是他做的.
Maggie: Of course he realizes it. He did it.
杰森:冷静一点.
Jason: Calm down.
麦琪:好,杰森,我肯定不能让他这样骗我而不受惩罚.
Maggie: Well Jason, I certainly can't let him get away with lying to me.
杰森:哦,是的,你可以,等一下.
Jason: Oh yes you can, wait a bit.
麦琪:我可以.
Maggie: I can.
杰森:他撒谎是为了遵守我们的合同.
Jason: He lied to you to honor our agreement.
麦琪:哦,那更重要?
Maggie: Oh and that's more important?
杰森:不是这样,我只是说最终我认为他展示了一些成熟和责任感.他实际上选择了去上课,我认为这直接源于我们给了他一点独立和空间,把他当成一个大人.
Jason: No, I'm just saying that finally I think he's showing a little maturity and responsibility. He's actually choosing to go to class. And I think that's the direct result of us giving him a little independence and space. Treating him like an adult.
麦琪:哦,如果你认为这是你的合同在起作用,那我这次可以放过迈克一马.
Maggie: Oh if you're convinced that you're agreement is working, I can hold off talking to Mike.
杰森:起的作用比我想象中的还好.
Jason: It's working better than I dreamed.
麦琪:好的!现在我需要钱去购物,
Maggie: Good! Now I need cash for the market,
你能把我给迈克,
can you give me the money that I gave to Mike,
他用来付你租金的的钱给我吗?你明白,
that he gave you for the rent?
杰森,
You know Jason, if I didn't know better,
如果我不知道的话,我会以为迈克刚刚赖掉了他的租金.
I'd think that Mike just got out of paying his rent.
杰森:哦,我能帮你拿这些食物吗?
Jason: Oh can I help with those groceries?
麦琪:不需要.你的时间算得很精确,和平时一样.
Maggie: No. Your timing, as usual, is perfect.
杰森:不是这样,我躲在门厅里,
Jason: Not really, I was hiding in the hallway till I heard you close
听见了你的关车门声.
your trunk.
麦琪:已经行了,迈克帮了我.
Maggie: That's ok. Mike helped me.
杰森:迈克还在这儿?
Jason: Mike's still here?
麦琪:他真体贴,是他主动帮忙的.我得说,你是对的,等一下,这里少了一包东西.
Maggie: And he was so sweet about it. I didn't even have to ask. I mean, I got to hand it to you. You were right and wait a minute, there's a bag missing.
杰森:我们也要少掉一个儿子了.
Jason: Well, we're going to have a son missing too.
麦琪:是他拿的吗?
Maggie: You don't know that he took it.
杰森:拿了什么?
Jason: Took what?
麦琪:我们在说什么?
Maggie: What have we been talking about?
杰森:谈论迈克的事,他说他要去上课,
Jason: Talking about the fact that Mike is still here when he said he
事实是他还在这.
was going to class.
麦琪:我们?
Maggie: We were?
杰森:是的,麦琪,他骗了我.
Jason: Yes Maggie. He lied to me.
麦琪:你看上去很伤心.
Maggie: You seem upset.
杰森:当然我会伤心,要是你呢?
Jason: Of course I am. Wouldn't you be?
麦琪:我也会,过去会,现在也会.我们去和他谈.
Maggie: I would. I was. I am. Let's go talk to him.
杰森:不,麦琪,
Jason: No Maggie. Wait a minute.
等一下.对于我来说,
The easiest thing in the world for me to do would be to go up there
世上最简单的事就是去那儿,教训一下他这个宠坏的孩子.
and treat him like a spoilt child.
但是我们商议过,我们要给他一些空间,
But we agreed, we're going to give him some room, some freedom.
一些自由,包括犯错的自由.
The freedom to fail.
麦琪:我们给了他自由,但他失败了.我们走.
Maggie: we gave him the freedom, he failed. Let's go.
杰森:麦琪,不.
Jason: Maggie, no. There's got to be a way to get some action without
我们得采取一些措施,而又不能违反合同.
violating our agreement.
迈克:嘿.
Mike: Hey.
杰森:抱歉,迈克.我肯定是剪刀用得不小心.
Jason: Sorry Mike, I must have got a little careless with these clippers.
波纳:我爸爸也是一样.
Boner: Same thing happens with my baba.
杰森:波纳!
Jason: Boner!
杰森:是你,只有你!
Jason: The one and only.
杰森:迈克在哪?
Jason: Well where's Mike?
波纳:他刚走了,他有一堂历史课,
Boner: Just missed him.
他需要有人在这等一份投递.
He had a history class and he needed someone to wait here for a delivery.
杰森:我以为他的课半小时前就开始了.
Jason: I thought his class started half an hour ago.
波纳:是的.
Boner: Oh it did.
杰森:我想上一点课总比什么也不上好.
Jason: Well I guess a little class is better than none.
波纳!那正是我的座右铭.
Boner: That's my motto.
杰森:波纳,你说你在等投递.
Jason: Boner, you said you were waiting for a delivery?
波纳:不,我没有说.
Boner: No. I didn't.
杰森:你说了.
Jason: Yes you did.
波纳:糟了,我没想告诉你.
Boner: Darn. I wasn't supposed to tell you.
杰森:你还有什么不想告诉我的?
Jason: What else weren't you supposed to tell me?
波纳!好的,迈克买了一个……不,西维尔医生,你总是捉弄我.
Boner: Well that Mike bought a....don't Doctor Seaver. You almost tricked me.
杰森:我这样做很愚蠢.
Jason: I was foolish to try.
波纳:你介意我们不再谈话吗,我不相信你.
Boner: Listen, do you mind if we don't talk anymore, cos I don't trust myself.
杰森:好吧.
Boner: Thanks. Though, I've got to hand it to you , doctor Seaver, I think it's great that you are letting Mike move out, screw around and stay out all night, miss classes, and not yelling at him or anything. That's what I call being a decent father.
波纳:谢谢.尽管我已经对你说了,西维尔医生,我觉你能让迈克搬出去确实很了不起,整晚出去闲逛,逃课,你也不会训斥他.这是我眼中的完美父亲.
Jason: Ok.
杰森:你知道听到你说的这些话对我意味着什么吗,波纳?
Jason: You have no idea what hearing you say that means to me Boner.
波纳:我只是说如果我在厕所里待上十分钟,我爸爸就会变得紧张.
Boner: I mean my dad gets nervous if I spend more than five minutes in
你能想象如果我花了三百块买一张水床,
the bathroom. Can you imagine what he'd do if I spent three hundred bucks
他会怎样?天哪!
on a water bed? Woops!
迈克:嘿,爸爸.
Mike: Hey there dad.
杰森:嘿,迈克,一天很长吧.
Jason: Hey Mike. Long day?
迈克:是的,大学里可不是朝九晚五.
Mike: Yeah. College aint no nine to five job.
杰森:饿了?
Jason: Hungry?
迈克:是的,有一点.
Mike: Yeah, just a little bit.
杰森:别吃那个冷香肠,我给你留着呢.
Jason: Well never mind that cold baloney. I saved you a plate.
迈克:谢谢.你真是太好了,爸爸.
Mike: Ah thanks. That's mighty nice of you dad.
杰森:吃热的有助于学习.
Jason: I good hot meal to help you study.
迈克:高中时可没有总是这样.
Mike: It didn't all through high school.
杰森:那是肉馅面包,绿豆,和土豆.
Jason: So that's meat loaf, green beans, and potatoes.
迈克:是的.这是什么?
Mike: Yep, sure is. What's this?
杰森:你的账单.
Jason: Your check.
迈克:你现在要我付钱?
Mike: You're charging me now?
杰森:是的.
Jason: Uh hu.
迈克:但是,爸爸.我们的合同中包括一日三餐啊.
Mike: But dad. Our agreement includes meal privileges.
杰森:只有你准时的时候.
Jason: When you're on time.
迈克:哦,就因为我晚了两个小时,
Mike: Oh, so because I'm a couple of measly hours late,
你要让我付钱?
you're going to make me pay?
杰森:我不是真的要你付,
Jason: Look, I'm not really charging you Mike. This is an object lesson.
迈克,这是一个教训,
I just wanted you to see that you're going to have to be more faithful
我只是想让你知道你必须更严格地对待我们的决定.
to our deal.
迈克:爸爸,如果这儿有人违反合同的话,那就是你.
Mike: Dad, if there's anyone who is violating our agreement, it's you.
杰森:等一下,是你没付房租.
Jason: Wait a minute. You're the one who didn't pay the rent.
迈克:我付了.
Mike: I did pay it.
杰森:哦,是的,
Jason: Oh yeah. With mum's money.
用你妈的钱.我们本来要谈这个,
And we were going to talk about that except we couldn't because you said
但是我们没能谈,因为你说你得去上课.
you were off to class.
迈克:我是上课去了.
Mike: I did go to class.
杰森:是的,迟到半小时.你为什么迟到,迈克?因为你在那儿等一份投递,你花钱买了一张水床,而这是你本应该用来付房租的.
Jason: Yeah, half an hour late. And why were you late Mike? Because you were out there waiting for a delivery of some water bed that you bought with money which you should have set aside for your rent.
迈克:你做了什么?雇了私家侦探,还是?
Mike: what did you do? Hire some private detective or something?
杰森:嗯,别转换话题.
Jason: Oh come on. Don't change the subject.
迈克:我没有.问题是你自从我搬出去以后,
Mike: I'm not. The subject is that you have been acting more like a dad
你采取了更多的行动,要比我以前住在这里的时候更多.
ever since I moved out, than you did when I lived here.
杰森:听着,我给了你完全的自由,
Jason: Look, I gave you total freedom mike.
迈克,不幸的是你表现出你不能驾驭它,
Unfortunately you showed that you can't handle it.
所以,现在我要把它收回.
So now I got to take it back.
迈克:你不能这样.
Mike: Well you can't have it.
杰森:什么.你再也不想我帮忙了?我的指导?
Jason: So what. So you don't want my help anymore? My guidance?
迈克:不用.
Mike: No.
杰森:哦,等一下.在你这样说之前,迈克,想一下,好好想一下.当然,我可以把你当成一个陌生人,就像一个房客,没有任何优惠,也不能扭曲这规定.我也可以当你是我的儿子,是的,偶尔干涉一下,但是包含了所有的爱和支持.现在,你想做什么,房客还是儿子?
Jason: Oh wait a minute. Just before you say that Mike, just think, think. Yeah, I could treat you like a stranger, like a tenant. With no freebies and no bending of the rules. Or I could treat you like my son. Now yes, there's occasional interference which goes along with that, but also all the love and support. Now come on. So what's it going to be, tenant or son?
迈克:我选择房客!
Mike: I'll take tenant!
杰森:哦,很好.如果那真是你想要的.
Jason: Oh fine. If that's the way you want it.
迈克:那正是我想要的.
Mike: That's the way I want it.
杰森:很好,如果你想要那个的话,
Jason: Well if that's the way you want it then. That's the way it will be.
那就是它了.从现在开始,我没有了儿子.
From now on, I have no son.
杰森:麦琪,我已经对这个孩子无能为力了.我用了我的爱,善意和理解来接近他.
Jason: Maggie, I have bent over backwards for this boy. I've approached him with love, kindness, understanding.
麦琪:这是什么?
Maggie: What's this?
杰森:哦,没什么.
Jason: Oh nothing.
麦琪:学生用肉馅面包,八块九毛五.
Maggie: Students meat loaf special, eight ninety five.
杰森:好吧,这是我给他晚餐的账单,
Jason: Ok that's the check I gave mike for his dinner.
那只是一个教训.
It was an object lesson.
麦琪:杰森,这样一个肉馅面包,你要我们的儿子付八块九毛五.
Maggie: Jason, you charged our son eight ninety five for your cruddy meat loaf?
杰森:我可以少要一点.
Jason: I could have charged a la carte.
麦琪:杰森,你在转换话题.
Maggie: Jason, you are missing the point.
杰森:如果你知道他从你这借钱的唯一原因是想买那个见鬼的水床,
Jason: How can you have this attitude when you know full well the only
你会有什么样的看法?
reason he borrowed money from you was to buy that stupid water bed.
麦琪:知道什么?
Maggie: Knowing what?
杰森:别装傻,我没说吗?
Jason: Oh don't play dumb. I didn't mention that?
麦琪:是的,你没说.
Maggie: No you didn't.
杰森:好,我是说,
Jason: Well I meant to. Ok, I should have.
我应该那样做.我们可以一个一个进行争论吗?
Can we fight about that after we fight about this?
麦琪:你告诉迈克他不能花钱去买一张水床了吗?
Maggie: Did you tell mike that he can't waste his money on a water bed?
杰森:没有.
Jason: No.
麦琪:那我去说.
Maggie: Then I will.
杰森:不,麦琪.听着,
Jason: No Maggie. Look, if he wants to be treated like a tenant,
如果他想被当成一个房客,那么我们就这样对待他.他不知道他放弃了什么?
then that's how we'll treat him. He has no idea what he's giving up.
麦琪:嗯,我们所知道的是,迈克有了自己的小屋,却不付租金,他还逃课,买了一张水床.
Maggie: Uh hu. So let's see. At this point Mike has his own place without paying the rent, he's skipping classes and he has a water bed.
杰森:他真天真,以为他得到了他想要的.
Jason: And he's naive enough to think he's got it made.
波纳:嘿,我们三个睡在这张床上,真是太棒了.
Boner: Hey, us trio of guys are going to have great times in this bed.
迈克:波纳!
Mike: Boner!
艾迪:闭嘴,波纳.迈克,我对我自己真感到难为情.我是说当我听说你搬到了车库顶上,而不是公寓,我还以为你要垮掉了.
Eddie: Shut up Bone head. Michael, I'm ashamed of myself man. I mean when I heard you were moving out over the garage instead of a real apartment, well I'll just say it, I thought you were wiping out.
波纳:乱嚼舌头!
Eddie: Hey you bite it. But I now see I was wrong.
You have got your parental units all wrapped around your little finger
you dog.
艾迪:嘿,你闭嘴吧.但是我现在知道我错了,你的父母已经被你攥在手心里了.
Boner: Bite your tongue!
迈克:不,我没有父母了.我的父母不认我了.
Mike: Nah, I don't have any units. My parents disowned me.
艾迪:你这个幸运的家伙.虽然这公寓没我的大,但是它还行.
Eddie: You lucky stiff. Now this apartment aren't quite as big as mine, but it will do.
迈克:好了,你是和你的表弟合租的.
Mike: Yeah, well you got to share yours with your cousin.
艾迪:是的,但是丹尼斯是丹尼斯,
Eddie: Yeah well, Dennis goes his way and I go mine.
我是我.至少我还没有和爸妈住在一起.
At least I still don't live at home with mummy and daddy.
波纳:嘿,我想搬出去,只是我不被允许.
Boner: Hey, I want to move out. I'm just not allowed to.
迈克:嘿,谁把水关了?
Mike: Hey, who turned off the water?
迈克:嘿,发生什么了?
Mike: Hey, what's going on?
杰森:我很抱歉,西维尔先生,
Jason: I'm sorry Mr.
除非房客付清租金,否则是不会有水的.
Seaver, but until the tenant pays his rent, there will be no water.
迈克:哦,爸爸.
Mike: Oh come on dad.
杰森:你爸爸在这儿?我很高兴见到他.
Jason: Oh, your father's here? I would love to meet him.
艾迪:你想做什么,迈克?
Eddie: So, what do you want to do Mike?
迈克:我不知道,你们想怎么做呢?
Mike: I don't know, what do you guys want to do?
艾迪:嘿,让我们看看喜剧频道吧!
Eddie: Hey, let's see what's on the ecstasy channel.
迈克:不,我的有线有问题.
Mike: No, I'm having cable trouble.
波纳:我明白,艾迪,我们可以去你家看电视.
Boner: I know what Eddie, we can go to your house and watch TV.
艾迪:哦,对不起,伙计们.我的表弟在搞聚会.
Eddie: Oh, sorry guys. Can't. My cousin's having a party.
波纳:哦,我要去
Boner: Oh, I'm into that.
迈克:很好,那儿会有很多女孩.
Mike: Alright. There are going to be tons of babies there.
艾迪:不.
Eddie: No.
波纳:我们可以去我家,
Boner: I know we could go to my house and see if my mum got a
看看我妈是否炖了一些什么.
crock pot.
艾迪:哦,嘿,我可以吃家常菜.
Eddie: Oh hey, I could use a home cooked meal.
波纳:迈克?
Boner: Mike?
迈克:不,不,
Mike: No no, you guys go ahead and do that family thing.
你们去吃家常菜吧.
I'm going to stay here and get something happening with my half empty
我得待在这儿,和我的半空的水床.
water bed.
波纳:我喜欢说它是半满的.
Boner: I like to think of it as half full.
艾迪:我觉得你只有一半的智慧.
Eddie: I like to think of you as a half wit.
迈克:再见,伙计们.
Mike: See you later guys.
艾迪:祝你愉快!
Eddie: Have a good time.
波纳:再见.
Boner: Bye.
迈克:太好了,我可以做我想做的了.这才是生活.
Mike: Yep, this is great. I can do anything I want. This is living.
杰森:抓住,本,是的,就是这样,投,
Jason: Hold on to it Ben. Yes that's it. Yes, swish. Almost swish.
差不多可以投了.很好,让我看看你怎么面对防守.准备好了吗?呵呵,
Good, let's see how you do against a little defense. Ready? Ho ho ho ho.
上篮,投进了.嘿,伟大的移动,儿子.
Up and in. Hey, great move son.
本:谢谢你教我,爸爸.
Ben: Thanks for showing it to me dad.
杰森:那就是父亲们该做的,
Jason: Well that's what fathers are for.
花些时间和他们的儿子在一起.等你们长大一点后,
Spending some quality time with their sons.
你们会感激的.
You'll appreciate that when you get a little older.
提到长大,本,
And speaking of getting older Ben,
该是增加你的零花钱的时候了?
isn't it about time I raised your allowance?
本:是的.
Ben: Say, it sure is.
杰森:一星期加10块怎样?
Jason: What would you say to another ten dollars a week?
本:能不能是20块?
Ben: How about we make it twenty?
杰森:我们排练过了,本.
Jason: We rehearsed this Ben.
本:你愿意给我20吗?
Ben: So you will give me twenty?
杰森:好的,给你,20元.
Jason: Well there it is lad, another twenty dollars.
本:做个长子真棒.
Ben: Gee being the oldest son is OK.
杰森:那足够了,本.
Jason: That's enough Ben.
本:如果我一辈子住在这,我也不会奇怪.
Ben: I wouldn't be surprised if I live here my whole life.
杰森:别这样.
Jason: Don't get carried away.
本:爸爸,当我长大后,我也绝不搬出去.
Ben: Man, when I grow up, I'm never moving out.
杰森:好的,该吃午饭了.本,那是什么?
Jason: Ok, it's about lunch time. Ben, what was that?
本:我是在演戏.
Ben: I was acting.
杰森:别靠它来计划?
Jason: Well don't plan a career on it.
本:爸爸,我尽力在做.
Ben: Gee dad, I did the best I could.
杰森:好的,我很抱歉.那很不错.
Jason: Yeah, I'm sorry. It was good.
本:现在那起作用了.
Ben: Now that was acting.
杰森:呵呵,喔喔!
Jason: Ho ho, ho, ho! Wow! Wow!
迈克:好的.
Mike: Yeah.
本:迈克.
Ben: Mike.
迈克:本!嘿,本,进来,进来.
Mike: Benny! Hey, Benny, come in, come in.
本:你是说进来?
Ben: You mean inside?
迈克:是的,当然.
Mike: Yeah, of course.
本:但是你说过我不能进去,喔,这床真是太棒了.
Ben: But you said I couldn't come in unless what a cool bed.
迈克:嘿,你想摸一下吧.
Mike: Hey, do you want to touch it?
本:那太好了!
Ben: Cool.
迈克:怎么样了?
Mike: So, what's going on?
本:我?
Ben: With me?
迈克:是的,你,妈妈,开萝尔和宝宝,你知道,所有人.
Mike: Yeah with you, mum, carol, the baby and uh, you know, everybody.
本:好的,开萝尔很紧张,
Ben: Well, Carol's in a panic because she gained a pound and a half.
因为她又胖了一点五磅.妈妈不和爸爸说话,爸爸不和妈妈说话,
Mum's not talking to dad, dads not talking to mum, and I made twenty bucks.
我赚了20块.这合法吗?
Is this thing legal?
迈克:是的,某些情况下是.嘿,你待在这吃晚饭吗?
Mike: Yeah, in some states. Hey, why don't you stay for dinner?
本:晚餐,嗯,我希望如此.
Ben: Dinner. Um, I'm supposed to.
迈克:我有你最喜欢的,烤豆.
Mike: I got your favorite, baked beans.
本:嗯,
Ben: Um, no, see, that's what I'm here for.
不,听着,
I'm supposed to invite you to a family dinner at that restaurant with
我来这儿是要请你去家饭店参加一次家庭晚宴
the ninety none foot salad bar.
迈克:家庭晚宴.嗯,谁邀请我?
Mike: Family dinner. Uh, who's inviting me?
本:我不能说.爸爸会杀了我.
Ben: Well, I'm not supposed to say. Dad would kill me.
迈克:爸爸!
Mike: Dad!
本:哦,不.
Ben: Oh, no.
迈克:别担心,本.我不会告诉爸爸是你泄露的.
Mike: No worries Benny. I won't tell dad that you spilled your guts.
本:谢谢.
Ben: Thanks.
迈克:很好,很好.爸爸请我去参加家庭晚宴,那真有意思.
Mike: Well, well. Dad is inviting me to a family dinner. Isn't that interesting?
开萝尔:你告诉爸爸你邀请了迈克?
Carol: Did you tell dad that you invited Mike?
麦琪:我没有告诉他.当你出嫁时,你才会明白.
Maggie: I didn't tell him anything. When you're married you'll understand.
本:妈妈!
Ben: Mum!
麦琪:你让迈克来和我们一起吗?
Maggie: Did you get Mike to come with us?
本:我相信我做到了.我还吃了他的豆.我真厉害.
Ben: I sure did. I got his beans too. Boy was I great.
他甚至以为是爸爸邀请他.撒谎真是有趣,不过你叫它演戏.
He even thinks dad invited him. You know lying is fun when you call it acting.
麦琪:太好了,本.我们上车吧.
Maggie: That's good Ben. Sort of. Let's get in the car.
杰森:好的好的.真是没想到.
Jason: Well, well. What do you know.
迈克:好的,真是没想到.
Mike: Yeah, what do you know.
杰森:你终于决定加入……
Jason: So you finally decided to join the...
迈克:我终于决定了!
Mike: I finally decided!
杰森:哦,我终于做了?
Jason: Oh, I finally did?
迈克:爸爸,是你邀请的我.
Jason: You wanted to be the tenant.
杰森:你想做个房客.
Mike: Dad, you're the one who invited me.
迈克:爸爸!如果你想让我来,尽管说.
Mike: Dad! If you want me to come, just say.
杰森:我是父亲,我要先说,行吧?
Jason: I'm the father. I'll talk first. Ok?
迈克:好的,我以为我没有父亲了.
Mike: Well I thought I didn't have a father.
杰森:我说我是一个父亲,
Jason: I said I was a father, not your father.
不是你的父亲.这个父亲正带上全家人去吃周末晚餐.
And this father is taking his family out to a Saturday dinner.
问题是你在这儿做什么?
The question is what are you doing here?
麦琪:我请了他.我们现在可以走了吗?
Maggie: I invited him. Can we please go now?
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
杰森:什么?那么我不去.
Jason: What? Then I'm not going.
迈克:好的,我不去.
Mike: Well I'm not going.
麦琪:好了,好了,
Maggie: That's it. That's it,
我不想站在这儿听你们两个榆木疙瘩.
I am not going to stand here and listen to the two of you butt heads.
迈克:你听见她叫我们什么?
Mike: Do you hear what she called us?
杰森:麦琪.你太激动了.
Jason: Maggie, you are getting so excited.
麦琪:我是激动,我应该在你们要像房客和房东那样,
Maggie: You bet I am.
而不是父子时激动.你们是一只吃了兴奋剂的公鸡,
And I should have got excited the minute you two started acting like tenant
很抱歉我这么说,但是迈克,
and landlord instead of father and son. I mean what a load of poppy cock.
事实是你不能只是一个房客,
Pardon my language. But the truth is Mike, you can never be just a tenant.
如果一个家长这么轻易地摆脱一个孩子,那他就是一个十足的混蛋.
I mean if it were that easy to get rid of a child who was acting
迈克,你逃课,
like a total jack arse, and lets face it mike, skipping class, lying,
撒谎,不付租金,
not paying your rent because you wasted it on a water bed,
因为你要买水床,也是一个十足的混蛋.
is being a total jack arse.
如果这么容易就能把孩子变成房客,那么美国每个家庭,
If it were that easy to turn your kids into tenants,
每个车库里都会住满房客,
there would be parents with renters in every home in every garage in North
还有加拿大.还有你,
America and Canada. And Jason, what burns me up is that you know better.
杰森,你知道很多,
But honey sometimes you've got the temperature on high,
当你让我很生气,因为你有时候总是头脑发热.
and nothing in the oven.
杰森:我是.
Jason: Well I'm.
麦琪:别打断我,我饿了.
Maggie: Don't interrupt me. I'm hungry.
本:我也是!
Ben: Me too!
麦琪:但是我不想出去了.我要做饭,给我的家,我完整的家.即使有人表现得像个大傻瓜.本,开萝尔,从车里出来.我要进去了,开始做晚饭.你们两个即使晚了两小时,甚至二十年,我的餐桌上也总会有你们的位置,而且没有任何代价.
Maggie: But I don't want to go out anymore. I want to cook for my family, my entire family. Even the ones who are acting like major loons. Ben, Carol, out of the car. So I am going to walk back inside and start to cook dinner. And if the two of you are two hours late, or even twenty years late, you will always have a place at my table. No charge.
开萝尔:喔!
Carol: Hu!
迈克:这些事让她很生气.
Mike: Boy, something bothering her.
杰森:是的.
Jason: Boy.
迈克:我认为她不应该这样对我们.
Mike: I don't think she should have treated us like that at all.
杰森:我也是.我是说她认为我们不讲道理,因为我们运用了一点点逻辑,来解决非常困难的……
Jason: Me either. I mean she thinks we are being irrational just because we applied a little bit of logic to a very difficult and kind of
迈克:是的
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:一种复杂性.
Jason: And kind of complex.
迈克:是的.你想怎么做呢?
Mike: Yeah. So what are you going to do?
杰森:我不想回去.不想.
Jason: Well I'm not going back in there. Not yet.
迈克:我也是.我要上楼去吃我的豆了.
Mike: Me either. Think I'm just going to go upstairs and eat my beans.
杰森:祝你好运.
Jason: Good luck.
迈克:谢谢.
Mike: Thanks.
杰森:好的,我要待在这儿了.
Jason: Yeah, I'm just going to stay out here.
迈克:你要待在这儿?
Mike: You're going to stay out here?
杰森:嗯.
Jason: Uh hu.
迈克:这里不冷吗?
Mike: Isn't it kind of cold?
杰森:没有厨房冷.
Jason: Not as cold as it is in the kitchen.
迈克:好的,再见.
Mike: Ok. See you later.
杰森:再见.
Jason: Yip.
迈克:嘿,爸爸.
Mike: Hey dad.
杰森:是.
Jason: Yes.
迈克:这儿.
Mike: Here.
杰森:这是什么?
Jason: What's this?
迈克:我剩下的租金.不是从妈妈那儿来的,
Mike: Rest of my rent money.
或者开萝尔,或者本.
And not a cent of it is from mum, or Carol or Ben.
杰森:你难为了波纳.
Jason: Well you cornered Boner.
迈克:你一点都不了解我,爸爸?
Mike: You really don't know me at all, do you, dad?
开萝尔:现在爸爸和迈克抱在一起了.
Carol: Now dad's got his arm around mike.
本:他可能想掐死他.
Ben: He's probably strangling him.
开萝尔:不,不.他们在笑.
Carol: No, no. They are laughing.
本:还在谈话.
Ben: And talking.
麦琪:谢谢你,上帝.开萝尔,布置餐桌,
Maggie: Thank god. Carol, set the table please. For five.
五份.开萝尔:在我做这个之前,我想确认一下他们是不是真的好了.
Carol: Before I do anything,
天哪,我相信了.00:23:05,800
I want to make sure that they are actually getting along. Damn it, I'm sure.